<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Brandontreb</title>
    <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/tags/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Brandontreb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 17:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/tags/articles/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trying Something New</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2018/04/15/trying-something-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2018/04/15/trying-something-new/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr: micro.blog is pretty cool.
I have recently been thinking about my process of blogging / tweeting / facebooking / etc.. and have realized that I&amp;rsquo;m burnt out on all three. I LOVE to write. I started one of the first successful iOS Blogs, published numerous (software development books)[http://manning.com/trebitowski], and have been blogging since 2008. Here are a bit of thoughts about the various platforms and ultimately my solution.
twitter Having over 4,000 followers on Twitter I used to find tremendous value in the platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Creating A Call Flow Can Help Your Software Sales Calls</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2017/04/07/how-creating-a-call-flow-helps-sales-calls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2017/04/07/how-creating-a-call-flow-helps-sales-calls/</guid>
      <description>In 2008, I was still in college. I had just landed my first job with a small consultancy as their first iOS developer replacing their outsourced Ukrainian team. Within my first week on the job, the CEO asked me to jump on a sales call as the technical lead. This absolutely terrified me. I remember doing things like ensuring that I had a full glass of water so my throat wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get so dry (it still did).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goals For 2015</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2014/12/29/goals-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2014/12/29/goals-2015/</guid>
      <description>It cannot be overstated that writing down one’s goals is critical to acheiving them. Pair that with sharing them with others who might help keep you accountable and your probabilty of achieving those goals goes way up.
With this in mind, I have decided to share my 2015 goals here on my blog in hopes that I will do a better job of acheiving them in the new year. I tried to focus on more measurable goals rather than things like “eat better” and “exercise more”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Development Consulting: Some Tips On Structuring Your Contracts</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2014/03/31/software-development-consulting-contract-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2014/03/31/software-development-consulting-contract-tips/</guid>
      <description>When I first started out as an independent software developer, one of things that stressed me out the most was how to structure contracts that I sent to clients. Working for a consultancy in my previous work-life I had seen contracts before, however, I never really paid enough attention to them to know what type of content went into them.
After quite a bit of research, I found an invaluable resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being An Indie Software Developer And Signing NDAs</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2014/02/28/indie-software-developer-signing-ndas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2014/02/28/indie-software-developer-signing-ndas/</guid>
      <description>Very frequently, I receive emails that go something like this:
“Hey Brandon, I have a killer project idea. Do you want to work on it? Please sign the NDA so we can talk.”
Early on when I first started consulting, I would have responded with something like “Sure send it over!” and signed the thing without hesitation. As of late, I have changed my view on NDAs; at least in this type of situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming A Software Consultant: My Backstory</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2014/01/31/becoming-software-consultant-backstory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2014/01/31/becoming-software-consultant-backstory/</guid>
      <description>I recently published a post about my first year of being an independent iPhone development consultant. The feedback from my readers was incredible, however there was one important thread on Hacker News that I wanted to address. The issues were:
One of my common hangups with these kind of posts is the lack of history as to what lead people to these consulting gigs. Where were you before, and how long were you there?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Learned In My First Year Of iOS Consulting</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2014/01/01/learned-first-year-ios-consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2014/01/01/learned-first-year-ios-consulting/</guid>
      <description>Wow, I can’t believe it has already been a full year since I struck it out on my own. Last year, I published a post after my first month on doing contract iOS development. Needless to say, I have grown and learned quite a bit over the past year and I wanted to share some of those experiences.
Income While I won’t share exact numbers, I left my 6 figure/year job to pursue the indie/consulting life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back To My Roots</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2013/06/12/back-to-my-roots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2013/06/12/back-to-my-roots/</guid>
      <description>I wrote my very first blog post back in July of 2008 when I start iCodeBlog.com. I started the blog because I saw a huge need for iOS development tutorials on the web and really wanted to help others as I progressed in my development.
Well, quite a bit has changed since then. I have written books, spoken at conferences, and built and shipped over 40 iOS applications. Since selling iCodeblog in 2009, I have really let my passion for blogging fizzle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&amp;#8217;s Your Cruising Speed?</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/10/05/whats-your-cruising-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/10/05/whats-your-cruising-speed/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year, I launched an application called Smart Lockscreen Creator. It was a pretty simple app that allowed you to add dynamic data (such as weather) to your wallpaper and save it back out to your camera roll. The idea is to improve the functionality of the user’s lockscreen. It did very well on launch (and even made it to #1 in the Israel App Store). At the peak, I was selling about 600 copies per day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Me At The Voices That Matter iOS Conference</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/09/07/join-me-at-the-voices-that-matter-ios-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/09/07/join-me-at-the-voices-that-matter-ios-conference/</guid>
      <description>In November, I will be attending the Voices That Matter iOS Developers conference. It will be my third time attending, and I can’t recommend it enough. One major change from this year however is, I will be attending as a sponsor. A new company/project (currently in private alpha) will be participating as a sponsor at the conference.
We intend to have a table set up with multiple computers and devices so you can check out our product first hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Great Pixel Art Tutorial And Free Resource Sites For Your Games</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/08/14/10-great-pixel-art-tutorial-and-free-resource-sites-for-your-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/08/14/10-great-pixel-art-tutorial-and-free-resource-sites-for-your-games/</guid>
      <description>I don’t usually create “list” posts, however I wanted to share a grouping of resources I have been collecting over the past few months. As you may have noticed, I’m a bit of a Pixel Art fanatic and wanted to share with you the tutorials that helped to get me started as well as some sites offering some high quality free pixel art.
Keep in mind that some of these sites have similar content, however they all take a slightly different approach in teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocos2D Tutorial &amp;#8211; Dynamically Coloring Sprites</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/07/30/cocos2d-tutorial-dynamically-coloring-sprites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/07/30/cocos2d-tutorial-dynamically-coloring-sprites/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever seen a game (such as Tiny Tower) that contains similar sprites that only vary by certain attributes (coloring, shading, accessories, etc…)? I would often wonder how long it would take the artists to create each permutation of these sprites. After discovering that you can call a method on a CCSprite called setColor, I realized how most of this customization is done in code.
This tutorial will be a continuation of my last post about creating your own Bitizen in Photoshop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pixel Art Character Tutorial &amp;#8211; Creating And Customizing A Bitizen</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/07/16/pixel-art-character-tutorial-creating-and-customizing-a-bitizen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/07/16/pixel-art-character-tutorial-creating-and-customizing-a-bitizen/</guid>
      <description>This will be a continuation of my last pixel art tutorial about configuring Photoshop for Pixel Art. For the past month or so, both my wife an I have been pretty addicted to this amazing game called Tiny Tower created by Nimble Bits. The biggest draw for me to this game isn’t the fact that it has great simulation style game mechanics, it’s the fact that it was created using Pixel Art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Photoshop For Pixel Art</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/07/02/configuring-photoshop-for-pixel-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/07/02/configuring-photoshop-for-pixel-art/</guid>
      <description>First things first. My wife and I had welcomed a new baby boy into the world on Monday so you guys are going to have to see the obligatory “dad” pics.
Here they are
Ok, now that’s past us, let’s chat about pixel art. I have always been a HUGE fan of pixel art both in games and as a form of art. As an aspiring game developer (games coming soon 😉 ), I found pixel art a great fit for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing iOS 4 In Action &#43; Free Chapter!</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/06/18/announcing-ios-4-in-action-free-chapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/06/18/announcing-ios-4-in-action-free-chapter/</guid>
      <description>Wow, I can’t believe it has been over a year since the release of my book iPhone And iPad In Action. Since then, we have sold over 6,000 copies and have just have released in numerous languages!
As with all iOS (tech books really), my book was almost outdated the moment it hit the shelves due to Apple’s constant SDK release cycle. My book ended with “here is what’s coming in iOS 4…”, and didn’t hit the shelves until after iOS 4 was released.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check Out AutoCorrector &#43; Promo Codes!</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/05/27/check-out-autocorrector-promo-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/05/27/check-out-autocorrector-promo-codes/</guid>
      <description>So, this blog post might sound like a lame press release, but I actually do want to talk about a cool app some buddies of mine created. Just read it in a cheesy used car salesman voice and it will be a lot less more enjoyable.
The Problem Have you ever tried to type shorthand text to a friend and it come out completely wrong? For example: AFK -&amp;gt; AFT, AKA -&amp;gt; Aja.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half Off iPhone And Android Books From Manning Publishing Today</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/04/14/half-off-iphone-and-android-books-from-manning-publishing-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/04/14/half-off-iphone-and-android-books-from-manning-publishing-today/</guid>
      <description>Last year I wrote the second edition of iPhone and iPad In Action. It was published by Manning Publishing and today they are offering half off all of their mobile software development books!
Simply use the code:
dotd0414 when you check out at manning.com for a half price discount on the following titles:
iPhone and iPad in Action That&amp;#8217;s mine! iOS 4 in Action iPhone in Practice Android in practice Hello!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Officially Running On Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/04/06/officially-running-on-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/04/06/officially-running-on-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Well, I have finally made the switch from WordPress to Jekyll and couldn’t be happier. Here are some of the bonuses I have seen thus far.
SPEED: Just click around on my site. It is screaming fast now. Resources: Checking top on my server reveals that I have a TON of extra resources (which makes sense since Jekyll sites are way more lightweight). Ease of blogging: Ok, WordPress was pretty easy too, however, I was really starting to get sick of the post interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free App Idea: Drop Tunes</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/03/01/free-app-idea-drop-tunes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/03/01/free-app-idea-drop-tunes/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps this already exists, if so, please link me to it.
The idea
Drop music into your Dropbox folder on your computer. Then open up the app which presents you with an iPod like interface for this music.
The genius
What’s great about it is, you have all of you music on your iPhone without using up disk space. Of course you may need to upgrade your Dropbox account to something greater than 2GBs to see any real value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Lockscreen Creator Released &#43; Promo Codes</title>
      <link>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/02/24/appstore1.png/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>brandontreb@gmail.com (Zero Cool)</author>
      <guid>https://brandon_swoop.ngrok.io/2011/02/24/appstore1.png/</guid>
      <description>My latest iOS app, Smart Lockscreen Creator has just released on iPhone for $.99.
Download It Here
The Idea Currently your lockscreen on your iOS device is nothing more than a pretty watch with a background. Jailbreakers have solved this issue with an incredible application called intelliscreen, which adds lots of interesting information to it. However, you and I are Apple fanboys and won’t violate our precious iPhones with jailbreaking. Enter Smart Lockscreen Creator.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
